onlineclock.net 2019-06-18

# OnlineClock.net Contact, Imprint & Privacy Policy

## Contact OnlineClock.net

Please feel free to contact us at any time with feedback about our website, questions or bug reports by sending your email messages to: 

info [at] onlineclock.net

We will respond eventually to all serious and important email messages sent to us. 

## Imprint for OnlineClock.net

Thomas M. Churm  
Hagelberger Strasse 45  
10965 Berlin  
Germany 

### Contact:

E-Mail: info [at] onlineclock.net 

### Responsible for Website Content:

Thomas M. Churm  
Hagelberger Strasse 45  
10965 Berlin  
Germany 

## Privacy Policy for OnlineClock.net

  1. **INTRODUCTION**

This privacy notice provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data through your use of our site **OnlineClock.net**.

By providing us with your data, you warrant to us that you are over 13 years of age.

**Thomas M. Churm** is the data controller and is responsible for your personal data (referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).

**Contact Details**

Our full details are:

Full name of legal entity: **Thomas M. Churm**

Email address: **info [at] onlineclock.net**

Postal address: **Hagelberger Strasse 45, 10965 Berlin, Germany**

If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([ _www.ico.org.uk_](https://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at **info [at] onlineclock.net**

  2. **WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymised data.

We may process certain types of personal data about you as follows:

  * **Technical Data** may include your internet protocol addresses, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, time zone setting and location, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this site. 
  * **Usage Data** may include information about how you use our website, products and services.

We may also process Aggregated Data from your personal data but this data does not reveal your identity and as such in itself is not personal data. An example of this is where we review your Usage Data to work out the percentage of website users using a specific feature of our site. If we link the Aggregated Data with your personal data so that you can be identified from it, then it is treated as personal data.

**Sensitive Data**

We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

  3. **HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We collect data about you through a variety of different methods including:

  * **Direct interactions:** You may provide data by filling in forms on our site (or otherwise) or by communicating with us by post, phone, email or otherwise, including when you:
  * Give us feedback or send us suggestions or bug reports
  * **Automated technologies or interactions:** As you use our site, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and usage patterns. We collect this data by using cookies, server logs and similar technologies. Log files on our web server are automatically deleted after several days' time. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites that use our cookies. Please see our cookie policy below for further details.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources:** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
  * Cloudflare, Inc. (our Web Security and Peformance provider)
  * Google / Google Plus / YouTube / Google's DART & AdSense
  * Instagram (via embedded Posts)
  * Analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU   
**Please note: we have anonymized IP collection in Google Analytics for all visitors. You can see this via the line of code "ga('set', 'anonymizeIp', true);" visible in our site's source code.**
  * Advertising networks such as Google AdSense and its partner networks based inside and outside the EU   
**Please note: starting May 25th, 2018, we will display only non-personalized ads to users in the EEA.**

  4. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when legally permitted. The most common uses of your personal data are:

  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation
  * To protect our website and web server against cyber-attacks
  * To serve personalized advertising, which is the sole source of funding for our website and its various web services

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal ground for processing the personal data described above.

**Purposes for processing your personal data**

Set out below is a description of the ways we intend to use your personal data and the legal grounds on which we will process such data. We have also explained what our legitimate interests are where relevant.

We may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground, depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please email us at **info [at] onlineclock.net** if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To administer and protect our business and our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)

| 

 (a) Technical

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure and understand the effectiveness of our advertising

| 

 (a) Usage

 (b) Technical

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy  
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences

| 

(a) Technical

(b) Usage

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy  
  
**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to find out more about how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please email us at **info [at] onlineclock.net**.

If we need to use your personal data for a purpose unrelated to the purpose for which we collected the data, we will notify you and we will explain the legal ground of processing.

We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent where this is required or permitted by law.

  5. **DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above:

  * Service providers who provide IT and system administration services
  * Security services who protect our website against malicious activity
  * Third parties to whom we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

  6. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

Countries outside of the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) do not always offer the same levels of protection to your personal data, so European law has prohibited transfers of personal data outside of the EEA unless the transfer meets certain criteria.

Many of our third parties service providers are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we do our best to ensure a similar degree of security of data by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission; or
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts or codes of conduct or certification mechanisms approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe; or
  * Where we use providers based in the United States, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the **EU-US Privacy Shield** which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

If none of the above safeguards is available, we may request your explicit consent to the specific transfer. You will have the right to withdraw this consent at any time.

Please email us at **info [at] onlineclock.net** if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

  7. **DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  8. **DATA RETENTION**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

  9. **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include the right to:

  * Request access to your personal data.
  * Request correction of your personal data.
  * Request erasure of your personal data.
  * Object to processing of your personal data.
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data.
  * Request transfer of your personal data.
  * Right to withdraw consent.

You can see more about these rights at:

https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at **info [at] onlineclock.net**.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

  10. **THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

  11. **COOKIES**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our cookie policy below.

## Cookie Policy

## Cookies In Use on This Site

### Cookies and how they Benefit You

Our website uses cookies, as almost all websites do, to help provide you with the best experience we can. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile phone when you browse websites

Our cookies help us:

  * Make our website work as you'd expect
  * Remember your settings during and between visits
  * Offer you free services/content (thanks to advertising)
  * Improve the speed/security of the site
  * Personalise our site to you to help you get what you need faster
  * Continuously improve our website for you
  * Make our marketing more efficient (ultimately helping us to offer the service we do at the price we do)

We do not use cookies to:

  * Collect any sensitive information
  * Pay sales commissions

You can learn more about all the cookies we use below

## Granting us permission to use cookies

If the settings on your software that you are using to view this website (your browser) are adjusted to accept cookies we take this, and your continued use of our website, to mean that you are fine with this. Should you wish to remove or not use cookies from our site you can learn how to do this below, however doing so will likely mean that our site will not work as you would expect.

### More about our Cookies

#### Website Function Cookies

##### Our own cookies

We use cookies to make our website work including:

  * Tailoring content to your needs
  * Remembering your preferences such as dates, alarm sounds, countdowns, etc...

There is no way to prevent these cookies being set other than to not use our site.

#### Third party functions

Our site, like most websites, includes functionality provided by third parties. A common example is an embedded YouTube video. Our site uses 3rd party functions from the following companies which use cookies:

  * YouTube - [Privacy Policy](https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines) powers the videos on our site
  * Google - [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) provides the ads, web analytics and other functions on our site
  * DART / DoubleClick - [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) provides the ads on our site
  * Cloudflare - [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/) provides security and performance-enhancing functions for our website
  * Instagram (part of Facebook) - [Privacy Policy](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875) provides embedded Posts (memes) functionality for our website

Disabling these cookies will likely break the functions offered by these third parties

####  Visitor Statistics Cookies

We use cookies to compile visitor statistics such as how many people have visited our website, what type of technology they are using (e.g. Mac or Windows which helps to identify when our site isn't working as it should for particular technologies), how long they spend on the site, what page they look at etc. This helps us to continuously improve our website. These so called "analytics" programs also tell us if how people reached this site (e.g. from a search engine) and whether they have been here before helping us to put more money into developing our services for you instead of marketing spend. 

We use:

  * Google Analytics - [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) helps us monitor our website's performance

#### Advertising Cookies

Cookies are widely used in online advertising. We only work with advertising partners who work to accepted privacy standards.

You can learn more about online advertising at [//www.youronlinechoices.com](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/) . You can opt-out of almost all advertising cookies at [//www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) although we would prefer that you didn't as ultimately adverts help keep much of the internet free. It is also worth noting that opting out of advertising cookies will not mean you won't see adverts, just simply that they won't be tailored to you any longer.

We use:

  * Google AdSense - [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)
  * DART / DoubleClick - [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) owned by Google
  * Other advertising network partners which advertise through or via the networks listed above

### Turning Cookies Off

You can control what information is collected via Google's Advertising Cookies on our site by following the information listed here: [https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

You can also switch cookies off by adjusting your browser settings. Information on how to adjust your cookie settings can be obtained via your web browser's help documentation.

More information on managing Cookies may be found by visiting these (or similar) links:
